Farhaan Mohammad Sa'ad Beeharry

Port Louis, Mauritius, 11611
+230 5707 6881 || contact@farhaan.info || Online Portfolio at farhaan.info |
linkedin.com/in/farhaan-beeharry

Personal Profile

I am a diligent Software Engineer at Information Technology ELCA Ltd with over 1 year of experience in commercial application development and a recent graduate of BSc Computer Science (Systems Engineering) from Middlesex University Mauritius with First Class Honours. I have experience in improving and updating existing projects, as well as developing new software functionalities. I am a creative and responsible professional with excellent problem-solving skills looking for a position as a Software Engineer.

Work Experience

Associate Software Engineer, August 2021 to Present

Information Technology ELCA Ltd, Saint-Pierre, Mauritius

- Working on 3rd Party Projects using Angular and Java.
- Utilised crucial design software skills to assist with projects.
- Effective changes and alterations based on specific design specifications.

Mobile Application Developer (Internship), May 2020 to August 2020

Navigation and Geocoding Technologies Ltd, Port-Louis, Mauritius

- Mobile Development of "Naveo Driver" Application using Flutter.
- Worked to solve complex problems using the latest Mobile Technologies.
- Writing source codes and making changes according to client's requests.

Trainee Network Engineer (Internship), May 2019 to August 2019

Secure Services Mauritius Ltd, Port-Louis, Mauritius

- Shadow Network Engineers in deploying and configuring of network devices.
- Ensured network security by developing and configuring network access.
- Analysed network components to identify beneficial improvements.

Education

BSc Computer Science (Systems Engineering) - First Class, 2018 to 2021

Middlesex University Mauritius, Flic-en-Flac, Mauritius

Cambridge Higher School Certificate - A Level, 2017

Royal College Curepipe, Curepipe, Mauritius

Cambridge School Certificate - O Level, 2014

Royal College Curepipe, Curepipe, Mauritius

Certificates

ELCAdemy, February 2022

Information Technology ELCA Ltd, Mauritius - Angular and Java Training

UoM Online Inter-University TechWar, March 2021

Second prize winner - Crackathon Challenge

DigiCup 2020 - Digital Solution Challenge, November 2020

Second prize winner - Mobile Application - Flutter

Introduction to Mechatronics - Using the Arduino Board, 2020

School of Electronics, Mauritius

Introduction to Programming Skills, 2017

RRJ Learning Centre, Mauritius

Introduction to IT - 2, 2015

RRJ Learning Centre, Mauritius

Australian Mathematics Competition (Yearly), 2010 to 2015

Royal College Curepipe, Mauritius (Organised by Australian Mathematics Trust, Australia)

Technical Skills

- Web development: HTML/CSS, Angular, JavaScript and TypeScript
- Mobile application development: Flutter (iOS and Android)
- Programming languages: Java (Spring / Spring Boot), Dart, PHP, Python and SQL
- · Tools: Jira, Git, Confluence, IntelliJ and Visual Studio Code

Professional Skills

- Ability to multitask Juggling different work activities and shifting attention between tasks
- Creativity Introducing new and innovative ideas with the use of imagination and originality
- Effective time management Effective coordination of tasks and activities
- Fast learner Pick up technical skills fast, tracking development and quick adaptability
- Problem solving Ability to handle problems, determine the issue and resolve

Projects / Relevant Experience

- Youth in Action DigiCup 2020 Competition project (Second prize winner) Flutter
- Flame Detection System Arduino and xBee
- Automatic Irrigation System Arduino, Flutter and Firebase
- Candidate Assessment System Angular and Java (Spring / Spring Boot)

Extra-curricular Activities

Event Organiser, October 2019 to June 2021

LaunchTech (Student Society), Middlesex University Mauritius, Flic-en-Flac, Mauritius

- Planned and delivered successful events at university and international level
- Designed posters using Adobe Photoshop, producing creative ideas
- Participated in two national level competitions. Got second prize for both

References Available Upon Request